[
    {
        "id":"1",
        "question":"What is PHP?",
        "options":[
            "PHP is an open-source programming language",
            "PHP is used to develop dynamic and interactive websites",
            "PHP is a server-side scripting language",
            "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"All of the mentioned"
    },
    {
        "id":"2",
        "question":"What does PHP stand for?",
        "options":[
            "PHP stands for Preprocessor Home Page",
            "PHP stands for Pretext Hypertext Processor",
            "PHP stands for Hypertext Preprocessor",
            "PHP stands for Personal Hyper Processor"
        ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"PHP stands for Hypertext Preprocessor"
    },
    {
        "id":"3",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax to write a PHP code?",
        "options":[
            "<?php ?>",
            "< ? php ?>",
            "<? ?>",
            "A and C Both"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"A and C Both"

    },
    {
        "id":"4",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct way to add a comment in PHP code?",
        "options":[
            "#",
            "//",
            "/* */",
            "All of the mentioned"
        ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"All of the mentioned"

    },
    {
        "id":"5",
        "question":"Which of the following is used to display the output in PHP?",
        "options":["echo", "write", "print", "Both (a) and (c)"],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"Both (a) and (c)"
    },
    {
        "id":"6",
        "question":"Which is the right way of declaring a variable in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "$3hello", 
            "$_hello", 
            "$this",
            "$5_Hello"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"$_hello"
    },
    {
        "id":"7",
        "question":"Which of the following is used for concatenation in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "+ (plus)", 
            "* (Asterisk)", 
            ". (dot)",
            "append()"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":". (dot)"
 
    },
    {
        "id":"8",
        "question":"How to define a function in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "functionName(parameters) {function body}", 
            "function {function body}", 
            "function functionName(parameters) {function body}",
            "data type functionName(parameters) {function body}"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"function functionName(parameters) {function body}"        
    },
    {
        "id":"9",
        "question":"Which of the following is the use of strlen() function in PHP? ",
        "options":[
            "The strlen() function returns the type of string", 
            "The strlen() function returns the length of string",
            "The strlen() function returns the value of string",
            "The strlen() function returns both value and type of string"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"The strlen() function returns the length of string"        
    },
    {
        "id":"10",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct use of the strcmp() function in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings excluding case", 
            "The strcmp() function is used to compare the uppercase strings",
            "The strcmp() function is used to compare the lowercase strings",
            "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings including case"
            ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings including case"        
    },
    {
        "id":"11",
        "question":"Which of the following function displays the information about PHP and its configuration?",
        "options":[
            "php_info()", 
            "phpinfo() ",
            "info()",
            "None of the above"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"phpinfo()"        
    },
    {
        "id":"12",
        "question":"Which of the following starts with __ (double underscore) in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "Inbuilt constants", 
            "User-defined constants",
            "Magic constants",
            "Default constants"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"Magic constants"        
    },
    {
        "id":"13",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following PHP code?",
        "options":[
            "no output", 
            "Welcome to Sanfoundry",
            "1000 PHP MCQ",
            "error"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "code":"<?php\n$x = 10;,$y = 20;\nif ($x > $y && 1||1)\n print '1000 PHP MCQ'\nelse\n print 'Welcome to Sanfoundry';\n?>",
        "ans_desc":"1000 PHP MCQ"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"14",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following PHP program?",
        "options":[
            "6", 
            "5",
            "4",
            "3"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "code":"<?php\n$fruits = array ('apple', 'orange', array ('pear', 'mango'),'banana');\necho (count($fruits, 1));\n?>",
        "ans_desc":"6"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"15",
        "question":"What will be the output of the following PHP program?",
        "options":[
            "Correct Answer", 
            "Is The",
            "I Wonder",
            "Which One"
            ],
        "ans":"3",
        "code":"<?php \n function multi($num)\n{\nif ($num == 3)\n echo 'I Wonder';\nif ($num == 7)\n echo 'Which One';\nif ($num == 8)\n echo 'Is The';\nif ($num == 19)\n echo 'Correct Answer';\n}\n$can = stripos('I love php, I love php too!','PHP');\nmulti($can);\n?>",
        "ans_desc":"Which One"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"16",
        "question":"In the following PHP program, what is/are the properties?",
        "options":[
            "function sample()", 
            "echo 'This is an example' ;",
            "public $name;",
            "class Example"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "code":"<?php\n class Example\n{\n  public $name;\n  function Sample()\n  {\n  echo 'Learn PHP @ Sanfoundry';\n  }\n}\n?>",        
        "ans_desc":"public $name;"
    },
    {
        "id":"17",
        "question":"PHP recognizes constructors by the name ________",
        "options":[
            "function __construct()", 
            "function _construct()",
            "classname()",
            "_construct() "
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":"function __construct()"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"18",
        "question":"What will be the value of the variable $input in the following PHP program?",
        "options":[
            "PHP stands for Hypertext <i>Preprocessor</i>!", 
            "PHP stands for Hypertext Preprocessor!",
            "PHP <td>stands for</td> Hypertext <i>Preprocessor</i>!",
            "PHP <td>stands for</td> Hypertext Preprocessor!"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "code":"<?php\n$input = 'PHP<td>stands for</td>Hypertext<i>Preprocessor</i>!';\n$input = strip_tags($input,'<i></i>');\necho $input;\n?>",
        "ans_desc":"PHP stands for Hypertext <i>Preprocessor</i>!"

        
    },
    {
        "id":"19",
        "question":"Which of the looping statements is/are supported by PHP?",
        "options":[
            "for loop", 
            "while loop",
            "do-while loop",
            "foreach loop",
            "All above"
            ],
        "ans":"4",
        "ans_desc":"All above"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"20",
        "question":"Which variable is used to collect form data sent with both the GET and POST methods?",
        "options":[
            "$_BOTH", 
            "$REQUEST",
            "$_REQUEST",
            "$BOTH"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"$_REQUEST"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"21",
        "question":"Which of the following function is used to set cookie in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "createcookie()", 
            "makecookie()",
            "setcookie()",
            "None of the above"
            ],
        "ans":"2",
        "ans_desc":"setcookie() "
        
    },
    {
        "id":"22",
        "question":"Which of the following function is used to sort an array in descending order?",
        "options":[
            "sort()", 
            "asrot()",
            "dsort()",
            "rsort()"
            ],
        "ans":"3",
        "ans_desc":"rsort()"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"23",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct way to create an array in PHP?",
        "options":[
            "$season = array['summer' , 'winter' , 'spring' , 'autumn'];", 
            "$season = array('summer' , 'winter' , 'spring' , 'autumn');",
            "$season = 'summer' , 'winter' , 'spring' , 'autumn';",
            "All of the above"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"$season = array('summer' , 'winter' , 'spring' , 'autumn');"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"24",
        "question":"The function in PHP that can be used to concatenate array elements to form a single delimited string is â€“",
        "options":[
            "implode()", 
            "concat()",
            "explode()",
            "concatenate()"
            ],
        "ans":"0",
        "ans_desc":"implode()"
        
    },
    {
        "id":"25",
        "question":"Which one of the following function is used to start a session?",
        "options":[
            "start_session()", 
            "session_start()",
            "session_begin()",
            "begin_session()"
            ],
        "ans":"1",
        "ans_desc":"session_start()"
        
    }

    

]